Michael A. Parker Papers VHP2004/15
CCSU Veterans History Project
Michael A. Parker Sr. Papers
Bulk, 1968-1970
1968 - 1970, 2004
VHP2004/15
CCSU Veterans History Project
123.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
Parker, Michael A., Sr., (Michael Anthony), 1950 -
Biographical/Historical note
Michael A. Parker joined the U.S. Marine Corps on July 22, 1968 just after graduation from high school. He attended boot camp at Parris Island, South Carolina, and after additional training in North Carolina and California, Parker was assigned to Danang Air Base in Vietnam. His first assignment in Danang was as a baker, and then later he was assigned to the mailroom on the base. In addition to the seven day a week job in the mail room, he also went out on patrols, or as extra help with reconnaissance at night as a machine gunner. He was discharged in February of 1970, and returned home to West Hartford, CT, where he worked as a firefighter.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged based on content and material type into 4 series:
Series I, Personal papers
Series II, Military documents
Series III, Publications
Series IV, Multi-media
United States. Marine Corps. Division, 1st .; United States. Marine Corps. Headquarters Company, Headquarters Battalion. .; United States. Marine Corps.; Camp Pendleton (Calif.); Parris Island (S.C.); Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Personal narrative, American; Ða` Na~?ng (Vietnam)
- Series I: Personal Papers
  - Interview Sysnopsis, April 16, 2004; VHP2004/15.I.1
- Series II: Military Documents
  - Letter to visitors at graduation, Perris Island, CA, Circa 1968; VHP2004/15.II.1; 2.0 Digital objects
  - First Recruit Training Battalion Letter to Michael Parker's relatives, October 25, 1968; VHP2004/15.II.2
  - Letter regarding Michael Parker’s discharge, Circa 1970; VHP2004/15.II.3
  - Michael Parker’s Honorable Discharge, May 19, 1974; VHP2004/15.II.4; 2.0
- Series III: Publications
  - U.S. Marine Profile 68, Circa 1968; VHP2004/15.III.1; 31.0 Digital objects
  - "Man with the Rifle" magazine, Circa 1968; VHP2004/15.III.2; 3.0 Digital objects
- Series IV: Multi-Media
  - Subseries A: Still Images
    - 1st Marine Division Headquarters, Hill 327 (Freedom Hill)—Da Nang, Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.01
    - Marching at Headquarters—Da Nang, 1st Marine Division, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.02
    - Marching at Headquarters—Da Nang, 1st Marine Division, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.03
    - Marine lastname Sherlock (nickname "Boston"), Headquarters—Da Nang, 1st Marine Division, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.04
    - Fire and somke on top of the hill near 1st Marine HQ, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.05
    - First Sergeant(Top Sergeant) Cooney, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.06
    - Barracks in 1st Marine Headquaters, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.07
    - “MP Valley” 1st Marine Headquarters - Da Nang, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.8
    - CH-46 Sea Knight helicopter landing at base - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.9
    - Motor Pool, 1st Marine Division Headquarters - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.10
    - Damaged building at 1st Marine Division Headquarters, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.11
    - Damaged building at 1st Marine Division Headquarters. [Might caused by shcokwave of the explosion of ammo dump (ASP-1) on hill 372 on April 27th, 1969 -- VHP archivist], Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.12
    - Damaged building at 1st Marine Division Headquarters. [Might caused by shcokwave of the explosion of ammo dump (ASP-1) on hill 372 on April 27th, 1969 -- VHP archivist], Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.13
    - Michael Parker in his “hootch” (a slang for a hut or simple dwelling, either military or civilian. Also spelledhooch), Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.14
    - Michael Parker - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.15
    - L to R: Michael Parker and Roy McNab - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.16
    - Michael Parker cooking - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.17
    - L to R: “Meeks”, Michael Parker, “Jocko” - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.18
    - Michael Parker in the bunk - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.19
    - Michael Parker sitting on bunker - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.20
    - Michael Parker on a bunker - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.21
    - Michael Parker and the dog “Gunner” - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.22
    - Roy McNab - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.23
    - Michael Parker - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.24
    - US Marine nickname “Frenchy” holding a mouse trap. He got the nickname because he taught English classes to the Vietnamese in French., Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.25
    - Michael Parker holding a picture of his girlfriend, Sheila Hurst, whom he later married - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.26
    - Michael Parker - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.27
    - Michael Parker in a bucker with 50 Caliber machine gun, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.28
    - R - L: Michael Parker, “Jocko”, and 2 unknown marines - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.29
    - Michael Parker and "Mann" on patrol - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.30
    - Michael Parker, on patrol - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.31
    - L to R: Juan, Ed, Joe, on patrol - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.32
    - Marines on patrol, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.33
    - Jensen, Michael Parker, on patrol - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.34
    - Michael Parker and Vietnamese soldier, Ha’, from Army of the Republic of Vietnam (ARVN), Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.35
    - Michael Parker with a Vietnamese soldier, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.36
    - Tank [M48 Patton-?] on patrol - Vietnam, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.37
    - Michael Parker, Marine in the center, leaning on truck, going on LP (listening post), Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.38
    - CH-46 Sea Knight helicopter on a recon mission, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.39
    - US Marine “Frenchy” teaching Vietnamese English lesson in French, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.40
    - South Vietnamese village, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.41
    - Vietnamese children, South Vietnamese village, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.42
    - Vietnamese child, South Vietnamese village, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.43
    - South Vietnamese villagers, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.44
    - Vietnamese child waring traditional Vietnamese hat (nón lá), South Vietnamese village, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.45
    - Evacuation of village, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.46
    - South Vietnamese children, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.47
    - South Vietnamese children, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.48
    - South Vietnamese children, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.49
    - Michael Parker giving Vietnamese childern a candy, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.50
    - Michael Parker giving Vietnamese childern a candy, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.51
    - Michael Parker giving Vietnamese childern a candy, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.52
    - South Vietnamese child on truck which Americans used to evacuate the children out of the village., Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.53
    - Lt. Hayes holding the a child on a truck which Americans used to evacuate the children out of the village., Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.54
    - Vietnamese on rice paddy, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.55
    - Michael Parker with Vietnamese children, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.56
    - Vietnamese children, Circa 1968 - 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.57
    - Audiences of Bob Hope Show - DaNang, Vietnam, Christmas of 1969, VHP2004/15.IV.58
    - Bob Hope giving signatures - DaNang, Vietnam, Christmas of 1969, VHP2004/15.IV.59
    - Arrival of Bob Hope by helicopter - DaNang, Vietnam, Christmas of 1969, VHP2004/15.IV.60
    - Bob Hope Show - DaNang, Vietnam, Christmas of 1969, VHP2004/15.IV.61
    - Bob Hope Show - DaNang, Vietnam, Christmas of 1969, VHP2004/15.IV.62
    - Bob Hope Show - DaNang, Vietnam, Christmas of 1969, VHP2004/15.IV.63
    - Bob Hope Show - DaNang, Vietnam, Christmas of 1969, VHP2004/15.IV.64
    - Bob Hope Show - DaNang, Vietnam, Christmas of 1969, VHP2004/15.IV.65
    - Michael Parker, Christmas of 1969 - Vietnam, VHP2004/15.IV.66
    - Michael Parker and fellow Marines (Marine on back row waring glass nickname "Trimmer"), Christmas of 1969 - Vietnam, VHP2004/15.IV.67
    - R to L:Michael Parker, Lewis (a sniper), unknown, Christmas of 1969 - Vietnam, VHP2004/15.IV.68
    - Michael Parker, Christmas of 1969 - Vietnam, VHP2004/15.IV.69
    - Christmas tree and nativity scene decorations, Christmas of 1969 - Vietnam, VHP2004/15.IV.70
    - First Marine Division Squad pick-up—Marines of Second Squad, Second platoon, Company A Boarding a CH-46 chopper after completing a sweep 11 miles southeast of Da Nang (U.S.M.C. photo by Sgt. Mike Adkison), 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.71
    - First Marine Division (Photo by L.Cpl. Rocky Pearson), January 21, 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.72
    - First Marine Division (Photo by L.Cpl. Rocky Pearson), January 21, 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.73
    - Crashed helicopter (U.S.M.C. photo; photographer unknown), 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.74
    - First Marine Division halipad (Photo by Cpl. G.J. Vojak), 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.75
    - First Marine Division Marines of Company L, Third Battalion, Twenty Sixth Marines move out to a CH– 46 chopper. The First Marine Division Leathernecks were de- parting for a Search and Clear Mission 10 miles North West of Da Nang. (Photo by L. Cpl. Rocky Pearson), 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.76
    - First Marine Division Marines of Company B, Third Battalion, Twenty Sixth Marines unload from the rear of a CH– 46 Sea Night Helicopter as their unit begins a Search and Clear Mission 10 miles North West of Da Nang. Photo by L. Cpl. Rocky Pearson), 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.77
    - Michael Parker back home in West Hartford, CT, 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.78
    - Michael Parker in uniform, after he returned from Vietnam, 1970; VHP2004/15.IV.79
    - Michael Parker at Veterans Dedication at Central Connecticut State University, 2006, November 21, 2006; VHP2004/15.IV.80
    - Michael Parker, West Hartford Residence, 2006, December, 2006; VHP2004/15.IV.81
  - Subseries B: Moving Images
    - Oral History Interview, April 16, 2004; 2004/15.IV.B.1; 2.0 dvd (Disk DVD VHP2004/14 #1, Disk DVD VHP2004/14 #2)
      Existence and Location of Copies note
      Interview video also available online.
      Streaming Video